Bavin Edwards, Senior Frontend Developer

Kingston, Jamaica, 18768590531, bavin_edwards@live.com

LINKS	LinkedIn, Portfolio, GitHub		
PROFILE	Passionate and experienced web developer with proven industry experience working in agile teams to deliver beautiful, responsive and user-friendly web applications. Experienced with creating component-based user interfaces, unit and integration testing, debugging, state management, authentication and code quality management.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Dec 2022 — Present	React Developer Consultant, Bitovi	Chicago, U	JSA (Remote)
	 Work alongside client teams to develop robust and beautiful web applications using industry best practice using NextJS, module federation and web components. Built a private npm enterprise package that allows micro front-end NextJS applications to publish analytic events through a shell application using Google Tag Manager. Built an enterprise package for micro front-end applications to publish logs through Microsoft Application Insights. Up-skill new and less experienced developers through one on one knowledge transfer sessions, on-call code review and peer development sessions. Write internal blog posts and training materials to help in knowledge transfers among out internal developers. Co-hosted a live, public training on the powers of web components. Major contributor to <u>@r2wc</u> v2 - an open source package that lets you convert a React component to a web component. Here is a <u>link</u> to the v2 announcement blog. 		
Oct 2021 — Dec 2022	Senior Web Developer, Alessa	Kin	gston, Jamaica
	 Attend weekly architecture meetings to decide on implementation of future features. Facilitate weekly code review sessions to promote growth, great code quality, and a solid understanding of the goals of the project. Review pull requests from other developers to ensure code quality, testing and robustness. 		
Oct 2020 — Oct 2021	Software Developer, Smart Mobile Solutions		gston, Jamaica
	 Developing Business Web and Mobile Applications using modern technologies and adhering to industry best practices. Created on-boarding Java SpringBoot course and accompanying assessment for new hires. Tech stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NodeJS, SpringBoot, MongoDB, Express, PostgresQL 		
EDUCATION			
Aug 2013 — Feb 2017	 BSc General Physics, University of the West Indies, Mona Engineering scholarship, sophomore year Graduated with honors 		gston, Jamaica
SKILLS	HTML5	NextJS	
	CSS	Web Components	
	Git	Module Federation	
	JavaScript	Vue	
	Typescript	Node.js	
	React		